Guide to the Richard Morford Papers TAM.361
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series I: Personal and Ministry Materials, 1918-1986
  - Consumer-Farmer Cooperative, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Peace Movement and Statements, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights: NY Metropolitan Area (Includes Bylaws), 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Consumer-Farmer Cooperative, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Presbytery of New York City, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Presbytery of New York City, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Presbytery of New York City: General Council, More Light, Program Departments, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Presbytery Reports, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Presbytery Study Group, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Religious Workers for Saving the Sacred Gift of Life from Nuclear Catastrophe: Moscow Conference, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Religious Workers for Saving the Sacred Gift of Life from Nuclear Catastrophe: Moscow Conference, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Religious Workers for Saving the Sacred Gift of Life from Nuclear Catastrophe: Moscow Conference: Portfolio (I), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Religious Workers for Saving the Sacred Gift of Life from Nuclear Catastrophe: Moscow Conference: Portfolio (II), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Religious Workers for Saving the Sacred Gift of Life from Nuclear Catastrophe: Moscow Conference: Portfolio (III), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Catholics for Free Choice, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Housing, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Church: General (I), 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Church: General (II), 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The Churchman, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, Housing, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Presbytery of New York City: Peacemaking, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Resort Places: Mohonk (New Paltz, NY), 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Union Theological Seminary, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Women's Concerns, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Peace Sabbath Peace Sunday Poster, May 1983 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Peace and Disarmament, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - National Council of Churches, World Council of Churches, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Oversize Poster, 1983 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 10, Folder 1)
  - Seventh Angel (Newsletter), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - New York City Churches, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Presbytery of New York City: Christian Education Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Presbytery of New York City: Personnel Department, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Riverside Church: Disarming Notes, Jun 1983-Jun 1985 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Consumer-Farmer Cooperative (Includes Housing), 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Gay and Lesbian (Includes Circle of More Light), 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Missionscope [Publication of Presbyterian Church (U.S.A.)], 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Presbytery: Education and Nurture, circa 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Presbytery: General (I), 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Presbytery: General (II), 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Presbytery: General (II), 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Washington Office of the Presbyterian Church, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Albion College, circa 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Notes on Cooperatives, circa 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Notes on House Un-American Activities Committee, circa 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Jewish Defense League, circa 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Onaway, MI: Notes and Clippings, circa 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights (I), 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights (II), 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights (III), 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Albion College Calendar, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Presbyterial Association, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Presbytery of New York City: Standing Rules (Revised) and Allied Materials, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Sanctuaries, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - United Church: Bay Ridge Sermon, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Albion College, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - The John T. Conner Center for US/USSR Reconciliation, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - West-Park Presbyterian Church, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Presbyterian Survey, Jun 1985 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Rescruitment Taskforce on Abortion, Sep 1985 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Albion College Reunion, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Housing, Nehemiah Plan, Consumer-Farmer Cooperative, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Nuclear Disarmament, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Presbyterian Advocacies: Central America, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Presbyterian Congress on Renewal, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Presbytery of New York City and Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Presbytery: Synod of the Northeast, etc., 1985 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Riverside Church: Housing Task Force, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Synod of the Northeast, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Women's Concerns, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Citywide Campaign for Family Life/Sex Education in New York City Public Schools, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights: New York Metropolitan Area, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Women's Concerns, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - "Christ of Everywhere" Souvenir Photograph, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Series II: National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1943-1986
  This series contains materials created and collected by Richard Morford as Executive Director of the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (NCASF) during 1946-1981 and as Executive Director Emeritus and member of the Executive Council during 1981-1986. Many of these materials document events and cultural programming organized by the Council, including exhibits, lists of films and books about the USSR for distribution to local councils, trade unions and schools, publications about the USSR, youth tours to the USSR and delegations from the US and from the USSR. Speeches, press releases, and other materials document the Council’s Annual Rally for Peace and Friendship held every in year in November in New York City. The Council’s response to current events, such as the formation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), the Warsaw Pact invasion of Czechoslovakia in 1968, and the Vietnam War are also documented in this collection. These responses can be seen in internal documents such as memoranda and in official statements, fact sheets, reports, articles in The New World Review, and press releases. Also included in this series are general administrative files, including financial documents, board materials, and correspondence, memoranda, and other materials related to other members of the NCASF, including William Howard Melish, Corliss Lamont, Alan Thomson, and Rockwell Kent. There are materials related to issues such as civil liberties and the McCarran Act, but the legal troubles of Morford and the NCASF in the 1940s and 1950s are not well documented.
  - House Un-American Activities Committee, Communism, Labor Unions, 1943-1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Tax Exemption Withdrawn, 1943-1948 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Outreach Materials and Correspondence, 1943-1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Reporter on American-Soviet Relations, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Red Army Dinner, Jan 1946-Feb 1946 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities Statement, Mar 1946 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - John Foster Dulles, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Rally Materials and Notes, Correspondence, 1946, circa 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Withdrawal of Sponsers, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Committee of Women, 1946-1952 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Let's Talk About Peace" Pamphlet, circa 1947 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Press Materials and Publications, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Truman Doctrine, 1947, circa 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Press and Outreach Materials, Feb 1948-Jun 1948 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Annual Report, Apr 1948 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Report on the News: Palestine, Apr 1948 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Statement Calling for Peaceful Settlement of US-USSR Differences, Jun 1948 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Dean of Canterbury, Sep 1948-Dec 1948 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Anniversary, Nov 1948 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Dean of Canterbury, Canterbury Dinner, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Stalin Proposals, Jan 1949-Feb 1949 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - North Atlantic Military Alliance, Jan 1949-Apr 1949 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - North Atlantic Military Alliance, May 1949-Aug 1949 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Statement on the Communique of the Foreign Ministers at the Paris Conference, Jun 1949 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - General Files (Includes Notes), Aug 1949-Sep 1949, circa 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Annual Rally: Speech by Jessica Smith, Nov 1950 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Administrative Files, Domestic Issues (Includes Notes), 1950, circa 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "End the H-Bomb Tests" Bumper Sticker, circa 1950-1955 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Financial Reports, 1950-1956 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Reception Honoring Dr. John A. Kingsbury, Jan 1951 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Event Materials and Publications, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Publications, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Event Materials and Clippings, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - New York Division, circa 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - New York Division, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Organizational Brochures, circa 1951-1982 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Joshua Kunitz, Jan 1952 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Field Trip, Feb 1952-Mar 1952 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - "Future of Germany and World Peace" Symposium, Mary van Kleeck, Apr 1952-Jul 1952 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous Notes on Activities to Supplement Annual Report, Apr 1952 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Administrative Materials, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - International Workers Order, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Peace Organizations, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Promotion Pieces for Literature, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Pamphlets on Amnesty for Smith Act, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Clergy "On China", Jan 1952 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Citizens' Emergency Defense Committee, Jan 1952 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Contributor Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - General Clippings, Publications, and Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Notes on Publications, 1952-1953, circa 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Rosenberg Case, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Statement Concerning a Letter, circa 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - American Labor Party, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Episcopal League for Social Action, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - New York Neighborhood Committees, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Phonograph Records, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Facts Correspondnce, Jan 1953 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Highlights of Activities with Supplement Notes, Jan 1953-Jul 1953 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Embassy, Mar 1953 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Fact Sheets, Notes, Correspondence, Mar 1953-Jun 1953 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Annual Report, Apr 1953 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Event Materials, Notes, and Publications, Jun 1953 - Nov 1953 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Highlights of Activities, Jul 1953 - Dec 1953 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Letter After Bishop Oxnam, Aug 1953 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - New World Review Censorship, Oct 1953 - Dec 1953 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - American Peace Congress and Exposition, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Annual Rally, Nov 1953-Jan 1954 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Peace Organizations, 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - New World Review Subscription Letter, circa 1953-1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Projection of Program for 1954, Jan 1954 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board Hearings and McCarran Act, Feb 1954-Jul 1954 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Report on Activities, May 1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Forum Flier, May 1954 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Religion in the Soviet Union, Aug 1954-Dec 1954 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Annual Rally, Nov 1954 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Peaceful Coexistence, Dec 1954 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Event and Press Materials (Includes Notes), 1954, circa 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Spanish Refugees, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Civil Liberties, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Books, Films, and Photographic Exhibits of the USSR, circa 1954-1960 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Defense of Right to Work for ASF, Dec 1955 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Event Materials and Contributor Correspondence, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report Covering 1955, Apr 1956 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Annual Rally, Nov 1956 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Corliss Lamont Correspondence, Nov 1956 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Events and Programming, circa 1956-1958 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Administrative Materials and Publications, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Middle East and Nuclear Disarmament, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Corliss Lamont, Mar 1958 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Program Guide, circa Sep 1958 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Cultural Exchange and Disarmament, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Kruschev Address Before United Nations, Sep 1954 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Administrative and Outreach Materials, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Article about NCASF, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Essays in New World Review, 1959-1969 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Administrative and Outreach Materials, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Auditor's Report, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Assorted Publications by Others, circa 1960-1965 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Oversize Poster, circa 1960-1965 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 10, Folder 1)
  - American and Soviet Printmakers Exhibition and Sale, circa 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Zilliacus Tour, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - McCarran Act, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Annual Rally, Nov 1962 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Youth Programs, 1963-1973 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Statement on McCarran Act, May 1964 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - "A Wilderness in Blossom: Notes on a Visit to Siberia", Sep 1964 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - American-Soviet Facts, Oct 1964-Dec 1964 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Speeches and Recollections, 1964-1983 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "In the Quest for Peace" by William Howard Melish, Oct 1965 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Annual Rally, Nov 1965 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - USA-USSR Friendship Society of Philadelphia, circa 1965-1980 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - 20th Anniversary as Executive Director, Jan 1966 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Outreach Programs, Dec 1967 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - The History of NCASF Article in New World Review, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - 2000 Words (Includes Notes), 1968, circa 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Press Release on Vietnam War, June 1968 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Board Materials Related to Invasion of Czechoslovakia, Sep 1968-Oct 1968 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Annual Rally, Nov 1968 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Anti-Ballistic Missile Fact Sheet Draft, Dec 1968 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Eugene McCarthy Advertisement, circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Statement and Purpose, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Vietnam War, circa 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Films, Photographic Exhibitions, and Books of the USSR, Jan 1969 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Mar 1969 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Rockwell Kent, Vietnam War, Apr 1969-May 1969 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Tours to USSR, circa 1969 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Board Correspondence, Sep 1970 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Library and Research Service, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Auditor's Report, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - General Files, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Brezhnev's Visit to US, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - USA-USSR Youth Meet, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Statements on US-USSR Relations, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Regional Memos, 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Annual Rally Programs, Nov 1975 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Local Societies Addresses, circa 1975-1985 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - November Institute Delegation, Oct 1976-Nov 1976 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Annual Rally, Nov 1976 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Estonia, Lithuania, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - National Conference, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Administrative and Board Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Delegation: Memos to Societies, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Press Materials and Speeches, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Meeting and General Files, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Agreements with Union Soviet Socieities for Friendship, 1976-1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Memo to Regional Socities Regarding Detente, Dec 1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Film Synopses, circa 1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Delegation to Moscow, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - General, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Neutron Bomb, Oct 1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Memos, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Auditor's Report, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - National Convention, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - East-West Trade and Job Development Project, Apr 1977-May 1977 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Spring Festivals, Apr 1977-May 1977 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Administrative and Programming Methods, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Memos and Correspondence, Apr 1979-Jul 1979 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - SALT II, Sep 1979 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Administrative Files and Reports, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Testimonial Dinner, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Canada-USSR Association, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Peace and Disarmament Clippings and Publications, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Citizens' Dialogue, Mar 1980-Jun 1980 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - June Appeal, May 1980-Jun 1980 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Gus Rystad Correspondence, Jun 1980 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Executive Committee, Jul 1980-Aug 1980 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - World Peace Congress, Sep 1980 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - National Board, Sep 1980-Dec 1980 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Executive Committee, Oct 1980 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Management Crisis Review, Oct 1980 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - New York Association Anniversary Meeting, Oct 1980-Nov 1980 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Announcement of Alan Thomson's Engagement, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Hank Teutsch, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Cable Exchanges with Moscow, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Union of Soviet Societies for Friendship, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Peace Action, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Board and Executive Committee Minutes and Memos, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Goodwill Missions Itineraries, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Alan Thomson's Memos and Fact Sheets, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - National Convention, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - "The Reds" Film, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Executive Committee and National Board, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Financial Documents, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Brezhnev, circa 1981 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - New York Assocation and Other Societies, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Young Workers Liberation and Forum for US-Soviet Dialogue, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Alan Thomson's Memos and Fact Sheets, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - El Salvador and Caribbean, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Executive Committee, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - In the Name of Humanity, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Miami Beach, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Movie Catalog, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Peace and Disarmament, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Tourism, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - New York Association and Other Societies, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - National Board, Mar 1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Executive Committee, Sep 1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - New Agreement, Thomson Letter, Oct 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 50th Anniversary USA-USSR Diplomatic Relations, Nov 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee, Dec 1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 40th Anniversary: The Philadelphia Story, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Clergy Tour, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - The Soviet Viewpoint, Georgi Arbatov, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Women Strike for Peace Legislation, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Alan Thomson's Memos and Fact Sheets, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Fact Sheets, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - General Documents, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - USSR-UN, Washington, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - General Publications and Clippins, circa 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Affiliated Societies, 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - New World Review Contributions and Fundraising, 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Notes on Attorney General's List (1947), circa 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Notes on Organization, circa 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Notes on Pamphlets and Major Publications, circa 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Notes on Publications, circa 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Notes on Young People, circa 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Press Materials and Clippings, 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Detroit Convention, May 1984 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Executive Committee and National Board Combined Meeting, May 1984 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Executive Committee and National Board, May 1984-Mar 1985 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Executive Committee, Aug 1984-Sep 1984 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Assorted Clippings, Correspondence, and Executive Committee Files, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Chess, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Ground Zero Memo and Text, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Lawyers Alliance for Nuclear Arms Control, National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - New Agreement, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Yalta, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Ward Book Review by Melish, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Bylaws, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Event Invitations: Embassy, Consulate, UN Missions, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - General, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Papers for Society for Cultural Relations L.A. Meeting, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - World Youth Festival for Peace in Moscow, Mar 1985-Apr 1985 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Executive Committee, Jun 1985-Sep 1985 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Executive Committee, Nov 1985-Dec 1985 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Publication and Event Materials, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Sister Cities Conference, Citizen Diplomat, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Executive Committee, Mar 1986 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Madison, WI Community Relations Strike Committee, undated (Box 11, Folder 50)